Guide to the Account Books Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Account books collection
1680-1925
MS 29
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
76
An artificial collection of account books and financial volumes, ca. 1680-1930, relating to such occupations as: farmers, merchants, traders, millers, blacksmiths, lawyers, manufacturers, laborers, physicians, shoemakers, carpenters, tailors, and cigar makers. Materials relating to private organizations and businesses are also included. The collection focuses on the Connecticut and New England region.
Arrangement
Arranged in three series and one addition: I. Volumes. II. Oversized Volumes. III. Numerical.
Scope and Contents
The Accounts Book Collection is an artificial collection of account books and financial volumes, 1680-1925, relating to such occupations as: farmers, merchants, traders, millers, blacksmiths, lawyers, manufacturers, laborers, physicians, shoemakers, carpenters, tailors, and cigar makers. Materials relating to private organizations and businesses are also included. The collection focuses upon Connecticut and the New England region. These volumes are a compilation of purchases and gifts for several years (ca. 1927-1958).
Volumes in SERIES I and II frequently relate to the same individual(s) and/or corporate body. Cross-references are provided to link appropriate volumes in each series.
SERIES I, VOLUMES, 1680-1911, and SERIES II, OVERSIZED VOLUMES, 1706-1903, contain business accounts and financial records in bound form, including account books, daybooks, ledgers, journals, and cashbooks. The daily financial transactions of individuals and businesses are recorded in these volumes. An individual or corporate body may be represented by a single volume or by several volumes from the type noted above.
Among the earliest volumes is one attributed to William Alley (1680) who commanded the Expectation, a ship of the East India Company. Many of the volumes record the financial transactions of Connecticut citizens in the eighteenth and nineteenth centuries. Accounts of farmers frequently record purchases of supplies and equipment while also documenting various other activities including the sale of produce, animals, crops, and other goods. Related transactions including the rental and lease of land, the hauling and transport of goods, and the fees for services such as masonry work, shoemaking, daily labor, weaving, carpentry, and other tasks are included
The financial transcations of merchants and shopkeepers detail the inventories of general stores, druggists, and store owners, in addition to recording the expenditure and receipt of cash transactions. The sale of a wide variety of goods, including meat, groceries, cloth, dry goods, shoes, hides, farm produce, wood, leather products, buttons, hats, and other items is recorded.
Several volumes which relate entirely or in part to shoemaking are located in the collection. Volumes for Leverett Allen, D.S. Barlow and Son, Elisha Bradley, Joseph and Reuben Bunnel, Simeon Chittenden, Asahel Clark, Abraham Cooper, Benjamin and Japhet Curtiss, Chandler Fay, William Fitch, Joel Morehouse, and Joseph Peck all contain records of shoemaking or shoe repair work performed as a business or as a supplement to farm work.
The volumes are frequently in poor condition with entries written in the daily course of business transactions, and thus not always legible.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Accounting -- Records and correspondence; Blacksmiths; Budgets, Personal; Business records; Business; Carpenters; Cigar makers; Debtor and creditor; Farmers; Industrialists; Inventories; Lawyers; Merchants; Millers; Physicians; Shoemakers; Tailors; Working class; Connecticut -- Commerce -- Accounting; Connecticut; New England; Account books
- VOLUMES, 1680-1919; Series I; 42 linear feet (100 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains volumes of business accounts and financial records arranged in alphabetical order by the name of the individual or corporate body. Unidentified volumes (boxes 94-100) are arranged in approximate chronological order and, whenever possible, identified by the geographic location and/or type of volume.
  - Abbot, Samuel, 1810-1846 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
    General
    See also: box 100A, folder 512A
  - Acorn Club of Connecticut, 1907-1919 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Adams, Ebenezer, 1839-1841 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Adams, Joseph, 1746-1801 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    General note
  - Allen, Leverett, 1826-1837 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Alley, [William?], 1680-1681 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - American Herald, 1784 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Andrews, Miles R., 1836-1855 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Andrews, Samuel T., 1825-1884 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Andrys, John and James Baldwin, 1848-1873 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Austin and Gilbert, 1850-1854 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Averill, Daniel
    See: box 100A, folder 513A
  - Babcock, Oliver
    See: box 100A, folder 514A
  - Baldwin, Daniel, 1819-1867 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Baldwin, D.S. and Son, 1856-1863 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Baldwin, James Judson, 1857-1885 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Baldwin, Reuben, 1808-1859 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Baldwin, Stephen and George, 1832-1852 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Barlow, D.S. and J.H.
    See: box 100A, folder 515
  - Bassett, Ellsworth F.
    See also: box 100A, folder 516
    - Daybook, 1879-1881 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Ledgers, 1870-1881 (Box 4, Folder 19-20)
  - Bassett, Harvey
    See also: box 101, folder 517-519
    - Ledger, 1848-1862 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Loose papers, 1832-1869 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Bassett, Isaac, 1818-1835 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Beach Brothers, 1854-1875 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Beecher, Lewis, 1813-1827 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    See also: box 103, folder 525
  - Belcher, William
    See: box 103, folder 526
  - Benham, Joseph, 1799-1811 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Benham, L.A., 1881-1891 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Betts, Asahel R., 1815-1820 (Box 6, Folder 28-31)
  - Berry, John
    - Account Book, 1821-1824 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Clippings, [ca. 1850] (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Bickley, Samuel, 1726-1849 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Blakeman, James, 1756-1830 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Booth, Charles
    See: box 7, folder 35
  - Booth, Orville, 1842-1880 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Bradbury, Reuben, 1809-1815 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Bradley, Elisha, [ca. 1745] (Box 7, Folder 38)
    See also: box 103, folder 528
  - Bradley, Silas A., 1875-1911 (Box 7, Folder 39-40)
  - Bradley and Wadsworth, 1808-1822 (Box 8, Folder 41-42)
    See also: box 104, folder 529-530
  - Brainerd, Elijah Newell
    See also: box 107, folder 537
    - Daybooks, 1867-1870 (Box 8, Folder 43-47)
    - Daybooks, 1870-1872 (Box 9, Folder 48-53)
    - Daybooks, 1872-1873 (Box 10, Folder 54-55)
    - Ledger, 1876-1888 (Box 10, Folder 56)
    - Small account books, 1868-1872 (Box 10, Folder 57-72)
    - Small account books, 1868-1870 (Box 11, Folder 73-75)
  - Brandegee, Elishama
    See: box 107, folder 538
  - Brockway, Charles Hallam
    See also: box 108, folder 541-542
    - Ledgers, 1819-1854 (Box 11, Folder 76-77)
    - Loose papers, 1827-1843 (Box 11, Folder 78)
  - Brown, Reuben, 1800-1822 (Box 11, Folder 79)
  - Brown, William Jr., 1830-1866 (Box 11, Folder 80)
  - Browne, Captain Francis (sloop Sledwell )
    See: box 108, folder 543
  - Bryan, Samuel
    See: box 108, folder 544
  - Buckingham, Abel, 1803-1827 (Box 11, Folder 81)
  - Bull, Jireh, 1808-1824 (Box 12, Folder 82)
  - Bunnell, Philemon, 1793-1811 (Box 12, Folder 83)
  - Bunnell, Reuben, 1799-1842 (Box 12, Folder 84)
  - Burbank, Charles, 1877-1879 (Box 12, Folder 85)
  - Buswell, John L., 1805-1843 (Box 13, Folder 86-87)
  - [Butricks, Henry G.?], 1860-1865 (Box 13, Folder 88-89)
  - Camp, David, undated (Box 13, Folder 90)
    See also: box 108, folder 545
  - Canfield and Seward, 1796-1824 (Box 13, Folder 91)
  - Carpenter, Gerald
    See: box 108, folder 546
  - Carrington, Nelson, 1847-1857 (Box 14, Folder 92)
  - [Carrington, William V. and George W.?], 1869-1870 (Box 14, Folder 93)
  - Carter, Lyman
    - Daybooks, 1837-1843; 1850-1857 (Box 14, Folder 94-95)
    - Ledgers, 1833-1859 (Box 14, Folder 96)
    - Loose papers, 1838-1866 (Box 14, Folder 97)
  - Chapman Manufacturing Company, 1891-1898 (Box 15, Folder 98)
  - Chase, Abner, 1811-1828 (Box 15, Folder 99)
  - Chatfield, Gideon
    See: box 108, folder 547
  - Chenango lands, 1786-1791 (Box 15, Folder 100-101)
  - Cheney, Susan, 1823-1849 (Box 15, Folder 102)
  - Chester, Edwin
    See: box 109, folder 548
  - Chittenden, K.S. and V.A., [ca. 1865] (Box 15, Folder 103)
    See also: box 109, folder 549
  - Chittenden, Simeon, 1821-1857 (Box 15, Folder 104)
  - Clark, Asahel, 1813-1838 (Box 16, Folder 105)
    See also: box 109, folder 550
  - Clark, David Smith, 1809 (Box 16, Folder 106)
    See also: box 109, folder 551
  - Clark, Jaleel, 1823-1851 (Box 16, Folder 107)
  - Clinton and Goodman, 1810-1814 (Box 16, Folder 108-109)
  - Cole, Nichols, and Company
    See: box 109, folder 552
  - Cook, Elam
    - Account books, 1866-1876 (Box 16, Folder 110-113)
    - Account books, 1851-1871 (Box 17, Folder 114-119)
    - Daybook, 1859-1863 (Box 17, Folder 120)
    - Ledger, 1859-1863 (Box 17, Folder 121)
  - Cook, John, 1860-1870 (Box 17, Folder 122)
    See also: box 110, folder 553
  - Cook, Thaddeus
    See: box 110, folder 554
  - Cooper, Abraham, 1812-1825 (Box 17, Folder 123)
  - Cornwall, Linus, 1853-1858 (Box 17, Folder 124)
  - [Cotton, John Burton?], undated (Box 17, Folder 124A)
  - Crane, Harrison
    See: box 110, folder 555
  - Crane, Zebulon, 1821-1849 (Box 18, Folder 125-126)
  - Curtis, Charles, 1827-1865 (Box 18, Folder 127)
  - Curtiss, Benjamin and Japhet, 1785-1816 (Box 18, Folder 128-129)
  - Curtiss, Erastus, 1836-1858 (Box 18, Folder 130)
  - Curtiss, Joseph and Simeon, 1783-1829 (Box 19, Folder 131)
  - Curtiss, Judson and Leavenworth A., 1860-1884 (Box 19, Folder 132)
  - Curtiss, Samuel C., 1814-1868 (Box 19, Folder 133)
  - Cutler and Babcock, 1812-1815 (Box 20, Folder 134)
  - Davis, David, Jr., 1816-1847 (Box 20, Folder 135-136)
  - Davis, James
    See: box 110, folder 556
  - [Dayton, E.C.?], 1894-1898 (Box 20, Folder 137)
  - Dehart, John Van Clef, 1815-1818 (Box 20, Folder 138)
  - Delameter, Jacob
    See: box 110, folder 557
  - Dewey, Christopher
    See also: box 110, folder 558
    - Accounts, 1788-1819 (Box 21, Folder 139)
    - Daybooks, 1808-1817 (Box 21, Folder 140-141)
    - "Records of Marks", 1825-1839 (Box 21, Folder 142)
  - Dewey, Thomas B., 1857 (Box 21, Folder 143)
  - Dewolf, George, 1854-1856 (Box 21, Folder 144)
  - Dexter, Normand
    See: box 110, folder 559
  - Dibble, Philo F. and Marcus Platt, 1827-1849; 1873-1885 (Box 21, Folder 145)
  - Dickerman, Chauncey Ailing
    See: box 110, folder 560
  - Dickerman, Eli, 1843-1868 (Box 22, Folder 146-150)
  - Dickerman, Jasper, 1827-1859 (Box 22, Folder 151)
  - Doolittle, Daniel
    See: box 111, folder 561
  - Dowd, C.H. and Company, 1851-1858 (Box 22, Folder 152)
    See also: box 111, folder 562
  - Dowd, Thomas, 1839-1840 (Box 23, Folder 153)
    See also: box 111, folder 563
  - Dowd, T.W. (Thomas W.), 1853-1859 (Box 23, Folder 154)
    See also: box 111, folder 564-566
  - Dowd, T.W. and Company
    See also: box 112, folder 573-574
    - Daybook, 1846-1849 (Box 23, Folder 155)
    - Ledgers, 1837-1853 (Box 24, Folder 156-158)
    - Loose papers, 1839-1846 (Box 24, Folder 159)
  - Down, Willis, 1834-1841 (Box 24, Folder 160)
  - Drake, James H., 1888-1894 (Box 25, Folder 161-163)
  - Dudley, Nathaniel, 1758-1794; 1841-1880 (Box 25, Folder 164-165)
  - Dunham, William P., 1827-1839 (Box 25, Folder 166)
  - Dutton, Henry, 1835-1867 (Box 26, Folder 167)
    See also: box 112, folder 575-576
  - Dyer, Daniel, 1836-1885 (Box 26, Folder 168-169)
  - Eagle Bank (New Haven, CT), 1818-1824 (Box 26, Folder 170-171)
    See also: box 112, folder 577
  - Edmond, Loevy
    See: box 114, folder 579
  - Edwards, Pierpont
    See: box 114, folder 580
  - Ellis Real Estate and Insurance, 1877-1897 (Box 27, Folder 172)
  - Ellis, Rufus, 1835-1855 (Box 27, Folder 173)
  - Elmer, Theodore, 1826-1830; 1851-1874 (Box 27, Folder 174)
  - Fairchild, Hiram, 1796-1890 (Box 27, Folder 175-177)
  - Farnum, Asa
    See: box 114, folder 581
  - Fay, Chandler, 1829-1842 (Box 28, Folder 178-179)
  - Fitch, Jonathan, 1799-1803 (Box 28, Folder 180)
  - Fitch, William, 1798-1815 (Box 28, Folder 181)
  - Ford, Amos and Stephen B.
    - Account books, 1794-1859 (Box 29, Folder 182-184)
    - Daybook, 1820-1829 (Box 29, Folder 185)
    - Loose papers, 1836-1851 (Box 29, Folder 186)
  - Ford, Elias
    See also: box 114, folder 582
    - Account book, 1832-1834 (Box 29, Folder 187)
    - Loose papers, undated (Box 29, Folder 188)
  - Ford, James E., 1821-1861 (Box 29, Folder 189)
  - Foster, George A., 1866-1896 (Box 29, Folder 190-191)
  - Frisbie, Samuel, 1793-1845
    See: box 114, folder 583
  - Frisbie and Stowe
    - Daybook, 1826-1829 (Box 30, Folder 192)
    - Ledger, 1821-1823 (Box 30, Folder 193)
    - Ledger, 1837-1838 (Box 31, Folder 194)
    - Loose papers, 1807-1823 (Box 31, Folder 195)
  - [Gabler, Peter?], 1877-1881 (Box 31, Folder 196)
  - Gates, Thomas, 1777-1792 (Box 31, Folder 197-198)
  - Gilbert and Company, 1869 (Box 32, Folder 199)
  - Gillette, Henry S.
    See: box 115, folder 584
  - Granger, William P., 1867-1882 (Box 32, Folder 200-201)
  - Grant, Clark Howe
    See also: box 115, folder 585-587
    - Daybook, 1848-1852 (Box 33, Folder 202)
    - Ledger, 1856-1888 (Box 33, Folder 203)
    - Ledger: foreign accounts, 1847-1891 (Box 33, Folder 204)
  - Grant, Miner, 1808-1829 (Box 34, Folder 205)
  - Green, Nathaniel
    See: box 115, folder 588
  - Grilley Company, 1866-1907 (Box 34, Folder 206)
  - Griswold, Leverett
    See also: box 115, folder 589
    - Daybook, 1835-1841 (Box 34, Folder 207)
    - Ledger, 1811-1836 (Box 34, Folder 208)
    - Ledger, 1823-1836 (Box 35, Folder 209)
    - Loose papers, 1830-1846 (Box 35, Folder 210)
  - Hale, Charles R., 1881-1895 (Box 35, Folder 211)
  - Hale, Elisha, 1806-1818 (Box 35, Folder 212)
  - Hall, Andrew, 1789-1812 (Box 36, Folder 213)
  - Hall, Benjamin
    See, box 116, folder 590-591
  - Hancox, Peleg, 1832-1834 (Box 36, Folder 214)
  - Hatheway, Samuel, 1790-1802 (Box 36, Folder 215)
  - Hatwell, Thomas H., 1857-1861 (Box 36, Folder 216)
  - Hawkins, Abijah, 1799-1844 (Box 36, Folder 217-218)
    See also: box 116, folder 592-593
  - Hawkins, George N., 1847-1848 (Box 37, Folder 219-220)
  - Hayden and Company
    See: box 116, folder 594
  - Hemingway, Samuel and Company, 1852-1869 (Box 37, Folder 221-222)
    See also: box 117, folder 595
  - Hemingway, Willis and Sons Company, 1897-1899 (Box 37, Folder 223)
    See also: box 118, folder 602-603
  - Hendee, Lucius Justin
    See also: box 119, folder 604-605
    - Journals, 1840-1841 (Box 38, Folder 224-225)
    - Journals, 1841-1845 (Box 39, Folder 226-228)
    - Journals, 1850-1853 (Box 39, Folder 229)
    - Ledger, 1839-1841 (Box 40, Folder 230)
    - Loose papers, 1835-1848 (Box 40, Folder 231-232)
  - Hickock, Benjamin S.
    See: box 121, folder 607
  - Hide, Abagail
    See: box 122, folder 608
  - Hill, John, 1754-1772 (Box 41, Folder 233)
  - Hill and Company; Hill and Upson, 1833-1840 (Box 41, Folder 234)
  - Hinman and Osborn
    See: box 122, folder 609
  - Hinsdale, Jacob, 1723-1774 (Box 41, Folder 235)
    See also: box, folder 610
  - Holbrook, Austin, 1826-1842 (Box 41, Folder 236)
  - Holmes, Rufus Edward
    - Journal, 1860-1873 (Box 42, Folder 237)
    - Ledger, 1860-1873 (Box 42, Folder 238)
  - Hopkins, John
    See: box 122, folder 611
  - Hotchkiss, Hobart LeGrand, 1873 (Box 42, Folder 239)
  - Hubbard, Daniel, 1837-1873 (Box 43, Folder 240)
    See also: box 122, folder 612
  - Hubbard, Leonard Chester
    - Farm accounts, 1798-1854 (Box 43, Folder 241)
    - Loose papers, undated (Box 43, Folder 242)
  - Hubbard, Samuel Goldsmith
    - Lumber accounts, 1879-1912 (Box 43, Folder 243)
    - Index and loose papers, 1890 (Box 43, Folder 244)
  - Hull, Henry C.
    - Ledger, 1897-1910 (Box 43, Folder 245)
    - Loose papers, 1894, undated (Box 43, Folder 246)
  - Hulme, Christopher, [ca. 1822-1859] (Box 44, Folder 247)
    See also: box 122, folder 613
  - Humphrey, Marshall, and Eliakim M., 1797-1832 (Box 44, Folder 248)
  - Humphreys and Spencer
    See: box 123, folder 614
  - Hunt, George V.R.
    - Account book, 1865 (Box 44, Folder 249)
    - Ledger, 1841-1846 (Box 44, Folder 250)
  - Huntingdon, Wolcott
    See: box 124, folder 615
  - Hurd, Jacob
    - Ledger, 1790-1855 (Box 44, Folder 251)
    - Loose papers, 1762-1861 (Box 44, Folder 252)
  - Huse, Abel, 1723-1803 (Box 44, Folder 253)
  - Hyde, William, 1787-1828 (Box 45, Folder 254)
  - Ives, Chauncey and Company, 1827-1833 (Box 45, Folder 255)
  - Jaclard, Daniel and Augustus P., 1857-1863 (Box 45, Folder 256)
  - Jobs, Sutton A., [ca. 1817] (Box 45, Folder 257)
  - Johnson, David, 1852, 1875 (Box 45, Folder 258)
    See also: box 124, folder 616
  - Johnson, Samuel, 1858-1873 (Box 46, Folder 259-260)
  - Kelsey, Aaron, 1763-1798 (Box 46, Folder 261)
  - Keyes, Edward S.
    - Accounts, 1797-1854 (Box 46, Folder 262)
    - Loose papers, 1817-1852, undated (Box 46, Folder 263)
  - Kilbourn and Coe
    - Ledger, 1829-1840 (Box 46, Folder 264)
    - Loose papers, 1840, undated (Box 46, Folder 265)
  - [Kimberly, Hobart?], 1857-1910, undated (Box 47, Folder 266)
    See also: box 124, folder 617
  - King, John
    - Farm accounts, 1812-1840 (Box 47, Folder 267)
    - Loose papers, 1837-1842 (Box 47, Folder 268)
  - Kinney, Woodbury
    - Ledgers, 1804-1825 (Box 47, Folder 269-270)
    - Loose papers, 1814-1824 (Box 47, Folder 271)
  - Lamb, Joseph
    See also: box 125, folder 618-619
    - Account books, 1846-1849 (Box 48, Folder 272)
    - Ledgers, 1849-1860 (Box 48, Folder 273-274)
    - Loose papers, 1852-1872 (Box 48, Folder 275)
  - Lane, Arthur, 1811-1844 (Box 48, Folder 276)
  - Landers, Hawley, 1836-1864 (Box 48, Folder 277)
  - Lathrop, Simeon, 1762-1803 (Box 49, Folder 278)
  - Learned, Edward, 1786-1849 (Box 49, Folder 279-280)
    See also: box 125, folder 621-625
  - Leavenworth, Andrew
    See: box 126, folder 630
  - Lee, James E.
    See: box 126,folder 631
  - Leere and Cornell, 1869-1873 (Box 49, Folder 281)
  - Leete, George C., 1850-1856 (Box 49, Folder 282)
  - Leete, Morris Atwell, 1854-1863 (Box 50, Folder 283)
    See also: box 127, folder 632
  - Limburner, John Jr.
    See also: box 127, folder 634
    - Cashbook, 1846-1847 (Box 50, Folder 284)
    - Loose papers, 1803-1812 (Box 50, Folder 285)
  - Lincoln, Jared Webb, 1858-1862 (Box 50, Folder 286)
  - Litchfield, Eleazer, 1800-1823 (Box 50, Folder 287)
  - Litchfield, Lorenzo, 1836-1846 (Box 50, Folder 288)
    See also: box 127, folder 635
  - Litchfield, Connecticut
    See also: box 127, folder 636
  - Lockwood, David
    See: box 127, folder 637
  - Long Island Democrat, 1875-1883 (Box 51, Folder 289)
  - Loomis, Luther, 1818-1827 (Box 51, Folder 290)
  - Lyman, David, 1787-1848 (Box 51, Folder 291)
    See also: box 128, folder 638
  - McCracken and Merriman, 1832-1837 (Box 51, Folder 292)
    See also: box 128, folder 639-640
  - McCulloch, Don Juan, 1879-1880 (Box 51, Folder 293)
    See also: box 132, folder 646
  - McDouall, John
    - Correspondence, 1770-1792 (Box 52, Folder 294)
    - Loose papers from accounts, 1770-1793 (Box 52, Folder 295-296)
    - Rental book, 1777-1793 (Box 52, Folder 297)
  - Madison Cash Store
    - Daybook, 1887-1889 (Box 53, Folder 298)
    - Ledger, 1875-1881 (Box 53, Folder 299)
    - Ledger, 1892-1895 (Box 54, Folder 300)
    - Loose papers, 1895 (Box 54, Folder 301)
  - Mallet, Gideon, 1838-1870 (Box 54, Folder 302)
  - Mansfield, Ebenezer, 1820-1843 (Box 54, Folder 303)
  - Martin, Anderson, Jr., 1799-1828 (Box 55, Folder 304)
  - Meech, Thomas and Stephen
    See also: box 133, folder 648-650
    - Daybook, 1809-1813 (Box 55, Folder 305)
    - Ledgers, 1811-1840 (Box 55, Folder 306-308)
    - Ledger, 1830-1855 (Box 56, Folder 309)
    - Loose papers, 1814-1826 (Box 56, Folder 310)
  - Merwin, Anson
    See: box 133, folder 651
  - Merwin, Caleb T., 1853-1869 (Box 56, Folder 311)
  - Merwin, Sidney, 1857-1872 (Box 56, Folder 312)
  - Miles, Stephen, 1826-1827 (Box 56, Folder 313)
    See also: box 133, folder 652
  - Mix, William, 1792-1820
    See: box 134, folder 654
  - Morehouse, Joel, 1828-1854 (Box 56, Folder 314)
  - Morse, Ebenezer
    See: box 134, folder 656
  - Moseley, William, 1790-1797 (Box 56, Folder 315)
  - Moseley, Jeremiah, 1830-1877 (Box 57, Folder 316)
    See also: box 134, folder 657
  - Mott, John T., 1801-1815 (Box 57, Folder 317)
  - Mott, Samuel
    See: box 135, folder 659
  - Mumford, Stephen
    See: box 135, folder 660
  - Nashua Iron Company
    See: box 135, folder 661
  - [New Haven Nut Co.?], 1882-1892 (Box 57, Folder 318)
  - Newell, Ashabel, 1817-1850 (Box 57, Folder 319)
  - North, E. and Company, 1856-1868 (Box 57, Folder 320)
  - Norwalk, Connecticut
    See: box 135, folder 662
  - Noyes and Company
    See: box 135, folder 663
  - Osborn, Ambrose, 1795-1853 (Box 57, Folder 321)
    See also: box 136, folder 666
  - [Palmer, Charles?], 1861-1876 (Box 57, Folder 322)
    See also: box 136, folder 667
  - Palmer and Hopkins
    - Account book, 1854-1859 (Box 58, Folder 323)
    - Daybook, 1852-1853 (Box 58, Folder 321)
    - Ledger, 1854-1860 (Box 58, Folder 325)
    - Ledger, 1856-1862 (Box 59, Folder 326)
    - Loose papers, 1856 (Box 59, Folder 327)
  - Parmele, Norman L., 1864-1890 (Box 59, Folder 328)
  - Parmelee and Hawley, 1866-1868 (Box 59, Folder 329)
  - Pease, Joseph
    - Accounts, 1795-1810 (Box 59, Folder 330)
    - Accounts, 1811-1836 (Box 60, Folder 331-333)
    - Loose papers, 1796-1840 (Box 60, Folder 334)
  - Peck, Bennitt
    See: box 136, folder 668
  - Peck, Hayden G.
    See: box 136, folder 669
  - Peck, Henry L. and Henry Smith; Peck and Somers
    See also: box 136, folder 670
    - Account books, 1874-1877 (Box 60, Folder 335)
    - Ledger, 1888-1892 (Box 60, Folder 336)
  - Peck, Joseph
    See: box 137, folder 674-676
  - Peck, Moses, 1818-1856 (Box 61, Folder 337)
  - Peck and Stafford, 1845-1846 (Box 61, Folder 338)
  - Pepper, Nehemiah, 1833-1842 (Box 61, Folder 339)
  - Philadelphia Southwark Union, 1836-1865 (Box 61, Folder 340)
  - Pierce, Ephran and Nathaniel, 1785-1838 (Box 62, Folder 341)
  - Pierce, Joel
    See: box 138, folder 677
  - Pierpont, Cornelius, 1857 (Box 62, Folder 342)
  - Platt, Fowler M., 1803-1837 (Box 62, Folder 343)
  - Pond, Henry, 1833-1845 (Box 62, Folder 344)
    See also: box 138, folder 678
  - Porter, W.D., 1831-1832 (Box 62, Folder 345)
  - Pratt, Taber, Jr., 1804-1811 (Box 63, Folder 346-347)
  - Preston, Almon
    - Ledger, 1810-1818 (Box 63, Folder 348)
    - Loose papers, 1851 (Box 63, Folder 349)
  - Preston, Titus, 1795-1817 (Box 63, Folder 350-351)
  - Redfield and Dudley, 1868-1891 (Box 64, Folder 352)
  - Reynolds, Samuel, 1785-1821 (Box 64, Folder 353)
  - Rich, William, 1840-1850 (Box 64, Folder 354)
  - Richards, Isaac, 1730-1754 (Box 64, Folder 355)
  - Richmond, George
    See: box 139, folder 681
  - Rockwell, Thomas H.
    See: box 139, folder 682
  - Root, Charles and George, 1835-1866 (Box 64, Folder 356)
  - Root, Charles and James, 1853-1854 (Box 64, Folder 357)
    See also: box 139, folder 683
  - Root, Mary E., 1836 (Box 65, Folder 358)
  - Russell, Lewis, 1806-1807 (Box 65, Folder 359)
    See also: box 139, folder 684
  - St. John, Samuel
    - Account book, 1828-1841 (Box 65, Folder 360)
    - Correspondence and papers, 1819-1846 (Box 65, Folder 361)
  - Safford, William
    See: box 139, folder 685
  - Sawyer, Jacob B., 1832-1844 (Box 65, Folder 362)
  - Scheiter, H.R.